Now you might think that the unambiguous if, then, else grammar is complicated and hard
现在你可能认为明确的IF，THEN，ELSE语法是复杂和困难的
to understand and frankly I would have to agree with you. Unfortunately, it's
为了理解，坦率地说，我不得不同意你的观点。不幸的是，这是
impossible to automatically convert an unambiguous grammar to an ambiguous one,
不可能自动将无歧义语法转换成歧义语法，
so we have to do these conversions by hand. If we're going to have unambiguous
所以我们必须手工完成这些转换。如果我们要有明确的
grammars, we have t o figure out how to write them by hand and that does result
语法，我们必须弄清楚如何用手写，这确实是有结果的
insignificantly more complex grammars and grammars that are hard to read and
微不足道的更复杂的语法和难以阅读的语法
maintain than if we use the, well more straightforward ambiguous grammars. A
维护比我们使用，更直接，更多歧义的语法。一个
possibility is to we'll try to somehow live with ambiguity cuz that will allow us
可能的情况是，我们会尝试以某种方式与模棱两可相处，因为这会让我们
more depth natural definitions. And, but then we would need some disambiguation
更深入的自然定义。然后，我们需要一些消除歧义的方法
mechanism. We need some way to tell which Parse tree we want when more than one
机械装置。当有多个解析树时，我们需要某种方法来告诉我们需要哪个解析树
Parse tree is possible. In fact, most practical parsing tools adopt the second
解析树是可能的。事实上，大多数实用的解析工具都采用第二种方法
approach. So, instead of rewriting the grammar, we used the more natural
进场。因此，我们没有重写语法，而是使用了更自然的
ambiguous grammar and the tool provide some kind of disambiguating declarations.
歧义语法和该工具提供了某种消除歧义的声明。
The most popular form of disambiguating declarations are precedence and
最流行的消除声明歧义的形式是优先和
associativity declarations. So, here is a natural grammar for plus over the integers
关联性声明。所以，这里有一个整数加法的自然语法
and this is ambiguous even just with a single infix operation, we can get
即使只有一次中缀操作，这也是模棱两可的，我们可以得到
ambiguity because this grammar doesn't tell us whether plus is left associative
多义性，因为这个语法没有告诉我们加号是否是左联想的
or right associative. And. So, simple solution here is to have associativity
或右关联。和。因此，这里的简单解决方案是具有结合性
declarations. So here, we declare plus to be left associative and this is the
声明。因此，在这里，我们将加号声明为左关联，这是
notation used in Bison. So, Bison is a particular tool and a present left plus
野牛中使用的记数法。因此，野牛是一种特殊的工具和现在的左撇子加号
declares that plus is a left-associative operation and so that would rule out this
声明加号是左结合运算，所以这就排除了这一点
particular Parse tree over here. Here [inaudible] more complex grammar
这里有一棵特别的解析树。这里[听不见]更复杂的语法
essentially the grammar we began with the, at the start of this video. Here we have
本质上，我们开始的语法，在这段视频的开头。我们这里有
plus and times over the integers and again this grammar is ambiguous because it
对整数进行加法和乘法，同样，此语法是不明确的，因为它
doesn't say what the precedence of times is with respect to plus. And the solution
没有说明时间相对于加号的优先顺序是什么。以及解决方案
for this is to have multiple associativity declarations. We declare plus to be left
因为这意味着要有多个结合性声明。我们声明把加号留下来
associative and we declare times to be left associative and then the precedence
关联，我们将时间声明为左关联，然后声明优先级
between plus and times is given by the order. So the fact here that times appears
加号和乘号之间是按顺序给出的。所以这里的事实是“泰晤士报”出现了
after. Plus means that times has a higher precedence than plus. Just one word of
之后。加号表示时间优先于加号。只有一句话
caution, These declarations are called associativity and precedence declarations
注意，这些声明称为结合性声明和优先级声明
but that's not what's quite what's going on inside the parser. The parser doesn't
但这并不是解析器内部正在发生的事情。解析器不会
really understand about associativity and precedence. Instead, these declarations
真正理解结合性和优先性。相反，这些声明
tell it to make certain kinds of moves in certain situations. We won't really be
告诉它在特定的情况下做出特定的动作。我们不会真的
able to explain this until we get much further into parsing technology, but just
在我们深入了解解析技术之前，我可以解释这一点，但是
be aware that we have to be a little bit cautious in using these declarations.
请注意，我们在使用这些声明时必须稍微谨慎一些。
Usually they behave like associativity and precedence in the way you expect but there
通常，它们的行为方式与您预期的结合性和优先级相似，但是
are some situations in which they will cause Rising behavior And is important
在某些情况下，它们会导致行为上升，这一点很重要
that you check the behavior of your grammar after you add these declarations.
在添加这些声明之后检查语法的行为。